牢记
Remember...
一定有什么想做但一直做不到的事情吧
There must be something that you always wanted to do but you couldn't.
我有很多想做的事
There are many things I want to do.
很好
Very good.
不管是什么事 无论要怎样做
Whatever it is, however it is done,
都要以做计划开始
you will start doing it with utmost planning.
应该有每日，每周，每月的计划
You should have daily, weekly, monthly plans.
不要走捷径，要把事情做细致
You won't cut corners. You'll make it complicated.
爷爷 你不记得了吗？
Dad, don't you remember anything?
爸 我要离婚了
Dad, I'm getting a divorce.
我给你介绍一个人
I'll introduce you to someone.
但这就是他的工作方式
But that's how he works.
-他是谁？-那个卑鄙的记者阿提斯·阿尔巴伊
- Who is he? - That charlatan journalist, Ates Arbay.
我曾经是一个热情的理想主义者
I used to be a fiery and an idealist reporter.
哦，可怜的阿加.
Oh, poor Agah.
你做了什么？
What have you done?
凌晨2点之后 -顾客离开 -锁门
AFTER 2 AM - CUSTOMERS LEAVE - THE DOORS ARE LOCKED
签名：阿加 贝尤鲁
LIFE BEGINS SIGNED: AGAH BEYOGLU
我现在该怎么办？
What do I do with him now?
他们的额头上写着“内芙拉”，这是怎么回事？
They had "Nevra" written on their foreheads. What's with that?
只是巧合 与我无关
Just a coincidence. It has nothing to do with me.
塞利姆，我有一个问题
Selim, I actually have a question.
你知道有人叫纳伊姆汉 ·图雷迪吗？
Do you know someone named Naimhan Turedi?
-纳伊姆汉- ·图雷迪出生于坎布拉
- Naimhan... - Turedi. Born in Kambura.
哦，是的，我知道
Oh yes, of course I do.
Yasin以前经常在车库里收集垃圾 他已经死了
Yasin used to collect trash over by the garage. He's dead now.
他们有个儿子，没什么用处
They had sons. Not good for anything.
他们都去了伊斯坦布尔
They all left for Istanbul.
叫穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔的法官怎么样？
How about someone named Mehmet Yurtgil? A judge.
-他被分配到这里吗？-不，他可能已经去世了
- He was assigned to here? - No. He might've passed by, though.
我不记得这个名字
I don't remember the name.
好的
Alright.
我要去跟警局的人聊一聊
I'll speak to the guys over at the station.
晚上过来吃饭
Come by again, though, this time for dinner.
你不来的话就别想回去
Don't even think about going back before stopping by one last time.
好的
Sure.
阿加 贝尤鲁在哪里，他是我父亲
Where's Agah Beyoglu? He's my dad. Where's my dad?
他出院了
He was discharged.
出院了？什么时候？
Discharged? When?
我睡觉的时候他就在那里，我醒来之后他就不见了
He was right there when I went to sleep. I wake up and he's gone.
他什么时候出院的？
When was he discharged?
祖哈尔女士，您的父亲匆忙离开，他给您留了张纸条
Ms. Zuhal, your father left in a hurry. He left you a note.
-爸爸？-在这
- Dad? - Over here.
爸 你在做什么？
What are you doing, dad?
我不分享细节怎么样？
How about I don't share the details?
这是什么纸条？
What is this note? Huh?
“我要去取车，家里见”
"I'm going to get the car. See you at the house."
我们都很担心你，你应该让我们知道的
We were worried sick. You should've let us know.
我不习惯让别人知道
I'm not used to letting people know.
自从你母亲去世以来，我一直没有让任何人知道任何事情
I haven't been letting anyone know anything since your mother died.
那是个借口！
That's some excuse!
我们真的很担心你！考虑下我们好吗？
We were worried sick about you! How about some thoughtfulness?
别喊了，反正我也听不见
You should really stop shouting. I can't hear you anyway.
是杀手还是受害者？
KILLER OR VICTIM?
坎布拉警察署
KAMBURA POLICE DEPARTMENT
内芙拉！欢迎！
Nevra? Welcome!
是我，乌拉尔
It's me, Vural.
-乌拉尔 -你看
- Vural? - See?
一旦有人离开了坎布拉，他们就把以前的事情都忘了
Once someone leaves Kambura, they forget all about their past.
你太伤我心了
You're hurting me.
-乌拉尔 -是的，乌拉尔
- Vural. - Yes, Vural.
抱歉，没认出你
Sorry, didn't recognize you.
当然了，伊斯坦布尔是另一个世界
Of course not. Istanbul is another world.
不过，我们一直在报纸上看有关你的消息
We've been reading all about you on the newspapers, though.
我看到你今天早些时候在开车，但在我打招呼之前你走了
I saw you driving earlier today, but you were gone before I could say hi.
欢迎
Welcome.
谢谢
Thanks.
-内斯林姨妈过得好吗？-很好
- How's Aunt Nesrin doing? Well, I hope? - Sure.
放心吧，我会自己修的
Don't you worry. I'll take care of it.
什么？
Excuse me?
车门，我会自己修的
Your door. I'll get it fixed.
真抱歉
What a shame.
我来修吧
I can take care of it.
算了……
Come on...
你不会很快回来坎布拉的
You're not coming back to Kambura anytime soon.
你不会的
You shouldn't.
至少让我付钱给你吧
At least let me pay for it.
你的钱在这里没有用
Your money's no good here.
-总之，再见了 -再见
- Anyway, goodbye. - Goodbye.
阿加！出来！
Agah! Come out!
伊斯坦布尔房价不是很贵吗？薪水怎么可能付得起？
Isn't Istanbul real expensive? How can you make it with your salary?
我付得起
I make do.
有任何信息吗？
Any information?
什么都找不到 他很久以前就离开了坎布拉
Can't find anything. He left Kambura a long time ago.
已经好几年了
It's been years.
从他们离开之后，没有任何信息
No info whatsoever since they've left.
但是我会告诉大家继续寻找
But I'll tell the guys to keep looking.
如果有消息我们会通知您
We'll let you know if we have something.
那你怎么做的？租房子吗？
So how do you make it? Do you rent your place?
阿加！
Agah!
出来！
Come out!
阿加！你躲不过我！
Agah! You can't hide from me!
我会把整个地方都烧掉！
I'll burn this whole place down!
来吧，我们一起吃
Come on, join us.
那么……
So...
坎布拉有什么变化吗
Does Kambura feel any different?
完全没有，还是老样子
Not at all. It's exactly the same.
我记得你小时候
I recall when you used to be a little girl.
你那时候几岁？
How old were you?
十
Ten.
从那以后我一直在向你妈妈示爱，她一直不感兴趣
I've been courting your mom ever since then. She's never interested.
意料之中
I'm not surprised.
我要杀了你
I'll kill you.
你太过分了
You're being too much.
萨利赫...
Salih...
好了，让我走吧
Come on, let me go.
我们可以各走各的
We can go our separate ways.
另外你受伤了，小心感染
Besides, you're wounded. Don't let it get infected.
是你先开枪打我，你个疯子！
You're the one who shot me, you lunatic!
那是误会，纯属意外！
It was a mistake! It was an accident!
你直接向我开了枪！怎么会是意外呢？
You shot me point blank! How is that an accident?
你是怎么找到我的？你一直在跟踪我吗？
How did you find me? Have you been following me?
我为什么要跟踪你？
Why would I be following you?
我的车坏了，你是第一辆驶来的车！
My car broke down and you were the first car to come by!
真是巧合！是天意！
It was a coincidence! It was fate!
我把枪收起来
I'm putting the gun away.
看到？
See?
我把枪收起来了，看到了吗？
I've put it away. See?
好了，你也把你的收起来吧，萨利赫
Come on, you put yours away, as well, Salih.
萨利赫...
Salih...
过来，让我们聊一聊
Come over and let's talk, brother to brother.
来吧
Come on.
还记得我们在坎布拉的谈话吗？
Remember our conversations back in Kambura?
你就像我的兄弟，来吧，别这样
You're like a brother to me. Come on, don't do this.
萨利赫...
Salih...
我以前每天去邮局只是为了看看你妈妈
I used to go to the post office every day. Just to see your mom.
我曾经寄假信件
I used to send fake letters.
但是我一直没有机会见到她
But I never got the chance to meet her.
突然有一天，他们告诉我她已经离开了
One day, they told me she'd left.
她来这里才六、七个月
It had only been six or seven months since she'd started here.
-她这么快就走了 -一年，我们住了一年
- She left so soon. - It was a year. We stayed for a year.
差不多吧
Give or take.
之后再没见到过她，但最终我还是得到了
I never got to meet her then, but I got her in the end, after all.
很好吃
It's delicious.
吃吧
Enjoy.
萨利赫
Salih...
来吧，我们聊聊吧，好兄弟
Come on, let's have a chat. We're brothers.
萨利赫...
Salih...
告诉我为什么？
Tell me, why?
这么多年过去了，你为什么要找我？
Why did you come after me after all these years?
你为什么要杀我？
Why did you try to kill me?
我对你做了什么？
What did I do to you?
真好笑
That's funny.
-那也是纳伊姆汉问的问题 -纳伊姆汉？
- That's what Naimhan asked. - Naimhan?
你对他做了什么？
What did you do to him?
你对纳伊姆汉做了什么？
What did you do to Naimhan?
告诉我！
Tell me!
萨利赫，如果这是我的终点……
Salih, if this is the end of the road...
那就让我自己来吧
Then let me do it.
-放下枪！-我不会放的
- Drop your gun. Drop it! - I'm not dropping it.
你他妈的快放下！
I'll fuck you up! Drop it!
在告诉我为什么要杀我之前，我不会让你死
I won't let you die before telling me why you tried to kill me.
告诉我为什么！
Tell me, why!
你为什么找我？
Why were you after me?
良心
Conscience.
良心？
Conscience?
什么良心？良心和这有什么关系？
What conscience? What does that have to do with anything?
你知道什么是良心，对吗？
You know what conscience means, don't you?
去尼玛的良心！
Fuck you and your conscience!
你都不好好看我一眼吗？
You won't look me in the eye?
已经三年了
It's been three years.
你已经三年没来了
You haven't come to visit for three whole years.
你把我踢出去的
You kicked me out.
你甚至都没有打电话
You haven't even called.
你告诉我不要打
You told me not to.
是啊，因为你辞掉了那份轻松的工作，去当警察了!
I did, because you left that cushy job and went and became a cop!
这些教育是为了什么？
What was all that education for?
你看现在怎么样？
See what it's come to?
你会惹上麻烦的
You might've gotten yourself into trouble.
你的名字，写在死者的额头上
Your name, written on the foreheads of dead men.
内芙拉...
Nevra...
我努力工作供你上学
I worked my ass off to get you through school.
我除了日常工作外还要做出纳员
I had to work as a cashier in addition to my day job.
但当那些没起作用的时候…
When that didn't do it...
你结了四次婚
You got married four times.
-那都是为了你 -为我吗？
- I did it all for you. - For me?
-那样你能有一个父亲 -因此我就不会成为妓女
- So that you had a dad. - So that I didn't become a whore.
继续说吧，这就是你一直说的
Go on, say it. That's what you've always said.
你好怕我会误入歧途 我一直不明白为什么
You were so scared I'd go astray. I never figured out why.
你想成为妓女吗？
Do you want to become a whore?
为什么？
Why?
我为什么会想？
Why would I?
你一定在我内心深处看到了什么
You must've seen something deep within me.
-别傻了 -你一定有
- Don't be silly. - You must have.
够了！
That's enough!
你为我结了四次婚！
You got married four times for me!
你救了我！
You saved me!
你真无私！
That was so selfless of you!
如此无私的你总会在屋子里围着一个男人
So selfless of you to always have a man around the house.
你做的一切都是为了不让我变成妓女……
All you did to keep me from becoming a whore...
在离开上一个人之前就与新男人相处
Getting with new men before even leaving the last one.
闭嘴
Shut up.
顺便说说
By the way...
我知道你没问，但是我父亲很好
I know you didn't ask, but my father's doing fine.
他没有打招呼，但很好
He didn't say hi, but he's fine.
你还称他为你父亲吗？
You still call him your father?
你父亲死了
Your father's dead.
那个叫尤克塞尔的混蛋
That bastard called Yuksel...
他不及你父亲的一半
He isn't half the man your father was.
是他给了你这些想法
He's the one who gave you these ideas.
是他让你成为了警察
He's the one who made you into a cop.
妈妈你为什么这么生气？
Why so angry, mom?
?？
Huh?
告诉我，你为什么这么讨厌生活？
Tell me, why do you hate life so much?
你为什么不爱我？
Why don't you love me?
别胡说
Stop speaking nonsense.
那你告诉我
Then tell me you do.
说“我爱你，我的女孩”
Say "I love you, my girl."
顺便说一句，我讨厌“ 妓女”这个词
By the way, I hate the word "whore", you know.
说出来就觉得脏
It feels so dirty when I say it.
我只能对你说这个词
You're the only one I can say it to.
当我和你在一起时我变得不像我
I become someone else when I'm with you.
像孩子一样，天真无邪的孩子
Like a child. A naive, innocent child.
这就是你对我的影响
You do that to me.
妈妈 我也爱你
I love you too, mom.
我也爱你
I love you too.
什么紧急情况？
What's the emergency?
我得了心脏病
I had a heart attack.
-好吧，进来 -谢谢
- Alright. Come on in. - Thank you.
心脏病？
A heart attack?
他现在还好吗？
How's he doing now?
他很好，他只需要休息一下
He's fine, he just needs some rest.
医生说他的心很强壮
The doctor said his heart was strong.
他满腔怒火，还不能死
He's too full of anger to die.
我在医院里，但是出了一些紧急情况
I was in the hospital, but something urgent came up.
我必须要去做一件事
I had to do that. I had to get there.
但是在去那里的路上，我忘记了应该做什么
But on my way there, I forgot what I was supposed to do.
阿加先生
Mr. Agah...
原谅我的直言不讳，但你得了心脏病
Excuse my bluntness, but you'd had a heart attack.
你在医院里有什么紧急的事？
You were in the hospital. What could've been so urgent?
那是我女儿祖哈尔的生日，我有礼物要送给她
It was my daughter Zuhal's birthday. I had to get her a present.
-你的女儿在这里？-我现在在这里
- Your daughter's here? - I'm here now.
找工作
Looking for a job.
什么都没找到
Still haven't found one.
不知道我该怎么办
Not sure what I'll do.
我想见见她
I'd like to meet her.
-我们甚至都没有打电话 -我知道
- We haven't even spoken on the phone. - I know.
你知道我会不请自来的
I'll come by unannounced, you know.
这不是世界的尽头
It's not the end of the world.
-如果你不开心，那就离婚 -我想这就是我们要做的
- If you're unhappy, then get divorced. - I guess that's what we'll do.
我跟梅布鲁雷说过很多次让她离婚，但她不听
I told Mebrure so many times to divorce him, but she wouldn't listen.
-人们有时候就是不听 -自找苦吃
- We don't listen, sometimes. - Did it both to herself and to us.
-对我也有附带伤害 -我的父母都很痛苦
- I was collateral damage, as well. - My mom and dad were miserable.
我愚蠢的妹妹
My dumb sister.
-装傻是不好的 -我恋爱了，她说
- Being dumb isn't good. - I'm in love, she said.
-我根本没有恋爱 -你妈妈太天真了
- I'm not even in love. - Your mom was so naive.
-她什么都相信 -但我不相信！
- She would believe anything. - I don't believe, though!
所以呢？
So what?
我以前一直撒谎，医生
I used to lie all the time, doc.
我小的时候
When I was young.
经常撒谎，这对我来说是第二天性
I used to lie so often, it was second nature to me.
快要疯了
It was almost a mania.
梅布鲁雷曾经相信我会说的话
Mebrure used to believe anything I'd say.
后来欺骗她让我感到害怕
Deceiving her started feeling horrible.
我恨自己
I hated myself.
我保证不会再对她说谎
I promised I'd never lie to her again.
我会像对待自己一样诚实对待其他人
I'd be as honest with everyone else as I was with myself.
唉……
Alas...
一旦我被这种疾病诅咒
Once I was cursed with this disease...
这种称之为阿尔茨海默氏病的让人遗忘的疾病
This forgetting disease called Alzheimer's...
我又开始撒谎了
That's when I started lying again.
你知道做为骗子最糟糕的是什么？
You know what's the worst part about being a liar?
必须记住所有的谎言
Having to remember all the lies.
我现在该怎么办？
What am I supposed to do now?
给你表哥打电话，我们可以一起打电话给他
Call your cousin. We can call him together.
他会找到适合你的工作，好吗？
He'll find you a job that suits you. OK?
你不需要留在你父亲身边，我就在这里
You don't need your father. I'm right here for you.
是他需要我们
He's the one who needs us.
他一直都不承认，但他才是需要我们的人
He's never accepted it, but he's always been the one who needs us.
他以为他不会做错事
He thought he could do no wrong.
梅布鲁雷把一切都给了他
Mebrure gave him everything she had.
我正在失去我的人格
I'm losing my personality.
太让人受不了了
It's too much to bear.
接下来我们这样做
Here's what we'll do.
-你不能忍受真相，你在说谎 -是的
- You can't bear the truth, you lie. - Yes.
-我们会一起发现那一刻的 -我们怎么做？
- We'll discover that moment together. - How are we going to do that?
从现实出发的那一刻
The moment you started running from reality.
以及为什么你一直在逃避
And why you keep running.
那就是我们要寻找的
That's what we'll go looking for.
但我不知道为什么
But I don't know why.
你可能不知道
You might not know.
但是你的记忆知道
But your memory does.
问问你的记忆
Ask your memory.
回顾过去
Go into the past.
去那些能让您回想起过去的地方
Go to the places that remind you of your past.
不管是什么使你恐惧
Whatever it is that's scaring you
都隐藏在你的过去
is hidden in your past.
找到它，阿加先生
Find it, Mr. Agah.
找到令你恐惧的真相
Find the first truth that terrified you.
阿提斯来电
INCOMING CALL ATES ARBAY
喂，阿提斯？
Yes, Ates?
到时间了吗？
Is it time yet?
什么时间？
Time for what?
您答应我的访谈，今晚可以做吗？
You've promised me an interview. Can we do it tonight?
我很忙，再约时间吧
I'm busy, Ates. Another time.
上次你找我的时候我可没让你失望哦
I didn't let you down the last time you called.
好吧，我们在哪里见面？
Fine. Where do we meet?
请给我一些空间，谢谢
Give me some space, please.
-嗯？-走开
- Huh? - Take off.
去哪里？
Take off where?
我在等人，那边也有座位
I'm expecting someone. There's an empty seat over there.
我哪都不去！
I'm not going anywhere!
我亲爱的亡妻很快就要来了
My dearly departed wife will be here soon.
去吧
Go on.
梅布鲁雷!
Mebrure!
我看见了
I saw that.
还没拍够吗？
Don't you have enough?
不要看镜头 看那边
Don't look into the camera. Look over there.
很快结束了
That's the last one.
就这样
Just like that.
保持这个姿势
Keep that pose.
好了吗？
Is it done?
没有
No.
保持住
Stay just like that.
就这样
Just like that.
别动
Stay...
快好了……
Almost there...
拍完了
I've got it.
总算好了
Finally.
让我们开始这次访谈吧
Let's get started on that interview.
德瓦？
Deva?
你去哪了？
Where have you been, Deva?
我告诉妈妈我要出去
I told my mom I was going out.
她没有问你会去哪里？
She didn't ask where you'd be?
-我不再为自己辩解了 -我不知道你像谁
- I don't explain myself anymore. - Who did you take after, I wonder.
-你好奇怪 -我知道
- You're so weird. - I know.
你知道……
You know...
我经常听说
I've been hearing about
青少年吸毒人数一直在增加
increased drug use among teenagers.
-你不吸毒，对吧？ -当然不吸
- You don't do that, right. - Of course not, grandpa.
很好 很好
Good. That's good to hear.
喝酒吗？
How about booze?
你买我就喝
Only if you're buying.
我知道了，谢谢
I've got it. Thank you.
我还想跟你以前的同事聊聊
I want to speak to your former colleagues, as well.
你曾经工作过的公司
From the company you used to work for.
你想知道什么可以直接问我
You can ask me whatever you'd like to know.
为什么？
Why?
因为我了解他们，但没人了解我
Because I know them all, but none of them know me.
很好，告诉我一些你想告诉我的事
Fine. Tell me something you'd like to tell me.
那是唯一适合你的问题
That's the only question that fits someone like you.
你想告诉我什么事？
What would you like to say, Nevra?
今天做了些什么啊？
What have you been up to today?
今天
Today...
我去了40年前我向你祖母求婚的地方
I went to the place where I proposed to your grandmother. It was 40 years ago.
- 谢谢你 -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
虽然
Though.
这次没有求婚
I didn't propose this time.
我想说什么
What I'd like to say...
我要抓到那个杀手
Is that I'm going to get that killer.
无论他跑到哪里
Wherever he runs to.
无论他躲在哪里
Wherever he hides.
我都要找到他并逮捕他
I'm going to find him, and arrest him.
你不相信我吗
You don't believe me?
我什么都不相信了
I don't believe in anything anymore.
我甚至不再相信自己
I don't even believe in myself.
但是我需要相信一个人
But I so need to believe in someone.
我多年来一直在报纸的封底上度过
I've been spending my years in the back pages of the newspaper
在那个DJ位上
in that DJ booth,
在那些招待会上
at those receptions I attend just to get fucked up,
在烂片的首映式上
at the shitty premieres of lame-ass movies.
感觉就像我由内而外腐烂
Feels like I'm rotting from the inside.
我甚至不忍心看那些照片的方向
I can't even bear to look in the direction of those photos.
你还留着它们
You still keep them up.
还在那里
They're still there.
那天我说了一个谎言，也许是我一生中的第一个谎言
I told a lie that day. Maybe the first lie of my whole life.
“ 梅布鲁雷，”我说，
"Mebrure," I said,
我会让你幸福
"I'll make you happy."
“拉着我的手，让我们从凳子上站起来
"Mebrure, take my hand, and let's get up off this bench,
让我们他妈的离开这里” 原谅我说了脏话
and -excuse my French-let's get the fuck out of here."
没有一点牵挂
Without a care in the world.
或者
Or...
“宝贝，忘了你曾经认识我”
"Mebrure, forget you ever knew me..."
“我不是个适合结婚的人”
I'm not made for marriage.
“我只会给你带来不幸”
"I'll only make you unhappy."
像这样
Something like that.
你根本不能喝酒，是吗？
You can't hold your liquor at all, can you?
你已经看重影了，你在哪……
You're already seeing double. Where are you...
去跟她聊天吧
Go talk to her. Go on.
想好了再说话，不然你会后悔的
Think about what you're going to say. You'll kick yourself later otherwise.
一个悲惨的灵魂，渴望得到关注
A miserable soul, desperate for attention.
你能为这样的反社会变态做的最大的帮助就是谈论他
The biggest favor you can do for such a sociopath is to talk about him.
但是，自谋杀案发生以来，您一直在关注这个案件
But you've been on this case ever since the murders started.
那不是对他有利吗？
Isn't that a favor to him, then?
我是记者
I'm a journalist.
我必须通知公众
I have to inform the public.
阿提斯，你一点都不害怕凶手会把你作为目标吗？
Ates, aren't you afraid at all that the murderer will target you?
看
Look...
就像他看着我一样
Just like he has his eyes on me,
我也能在房子周围看到你
I have my eyes on the perimeter of my house.
记住，没有人可以隐身
Remember, no one can turn invisible.
至少如此疯狂的人不会
Least of all someone so deranged.
这就是我所做的，你看到了吗
This is what I do, you see.
我在做演员
I'm in show business.
表演只不过是为了让人们忘记
The show serves one purpose only... To make people forget.
我正在忘记事情
I'm in the forgetting business.
-你对自己太苛刻了-这就是它的运作方式
- You're being too harsh on yourself. - It's how it works.
假设某处发生大屠杀
Let's say there's a massacre somewhere.
发生一次暗杀，但刺客从未被抓住
There's an assassination, but the assassin never gets caught.
我能让人们忘记他们
I make people forget about them.
发生过大型诈骗案吗？找我，我会让他们忘记
Has there been a huge fraud? Call for me and I'll make them forget.
怎么做？如何使他们忘记？
How? How do you make them forget?
像这样一个关于凶手的故事
With stories such as this one about the murderer.
我编了一个童话故事
I spin a fairy tale.
大家都屏息静听
They all listen with bated breath.
他被抓了之后另一个人出现了
He gets caught and another one emerges.
又被抓了，然后又出现一个
He gets caught, and another one.
我给他们讲故事，但是你知道我不做什么吗？
I tell all their stories. But you know what I don't do?
为什么这么多人可以携带枪支?
How come so many people are licensed to carry guns?
为什么人们可以如此轻易地获得枪支?
How come people can access guns so easily?
我从没说过
I never talk about that.
你明白了吗？
You got it?
如果你想让人们忘记枪
If you want to make people forget about the gun,
你所要做的就是谈论受害者
all you have to do is talk about the victim.
但我不再这样做了
But I'm not doing it anymore.
到此为止
I've had it up to here.
你会怎么做？
What will you do?
我可以讲脏话吗？
May I curse?
我会干他妈的
I'll fuck them up.
我不会让人们忘记
I won't let people forget.
你什么时候决定的?
When did you decide on that?
今天
Today.
准确地说，当我给你拍照时
As I was shooting you, to be precise.
你好骚啊
You're so sweet.
车！
The car...
祖哈尔...
Zuhal...
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
我们应该给你找个地方
We should get you a place.
属于你自己的地方
A place of your own.
那样你们俩会更舒服
You'd both be more comfortable that way.
他至少会有自己的房间
He'll have his own room, at least.
我能负担租金直到你找到工作
I can cover the rent until you get a job.
当你说你一直在想的时候，我以为你会像
When you said you'd been thinking, I thought you'd be like...
“我把楼下的公寓卖了，给你找个地方住。”
"Let's sell the apartment downstairs and get you a place of your own."
像这样
Something like that.
我不是没想过
It's not like I haven't been doing that.
四号房间，用于支付你高中的费用
Number four, covered your high school.
六号，大学的费用
Number six, your college.
七号，你的伦敦硕士学位
Number seven, your master's in London.
如你所知，三号支付了你母亲的治疗费用
Number three, as you know, went towards your mother's treatment.
我现在一个人在这个巨大的大楼里
I'm all alone in this huge building now.
-不过我们还有八号 -我告诉你我把它租出去了
- We still have Number eight, though. - I told you I rent that out.
我们可以告诉租户我们需要卖掉，可以和他们交谈
We can tell the tenants we need to sell it. I can talk to them.
不能跟他们谈，他们在用房间做仓库
You can't talk to them. They're using it for storage.
他们住在国外
They live abroad.
我可以打电话给他们，给我他们的电话
I can call them, then. Just give me their number.
当然我们也可以卖这套公寓
Of course. We can sell this apartment, as well.
你可以把我放在家里
You can put me in a home.
也可以把我扔到大街上
Even better, you can put me out on the street.
你知道你听起来有多自私吗？
Do you realize how selfish you sound?
这座建筑以你母亲的名字命名
This building is named after your mother.
你怎么能这么轻易放手？
How can you be so ready to let it go?
我们应该感谢我已故的祖父，对吗？
We should be grateful to my departed grandfather, right?
谢谢他把这栋楼交给我妈妈
For giving this building to my mother.
如果没有他我们该怎么办？
What would we do if he hadn't?
你怎么办？我怎么办？德瓦怎么办？
What would you do? What would I? What would Deva?
说出来
Say what you mean to say.
您到底想说什么？
What is it you'd like to say, exactly?
不要多管闲事
Don't stick your nose where it doesn't belong.
学学我，从不多管闲事
See how I don't stick my nose into your business?
我从没问过你为什么与丈夫离婚？
See how I never ask about why you got divorced from your husband?
学我怎么闭嘴，你尝试一下如何？
See how I keep my mouth shut? How about you try it out for once?
问我啊
Ask me, dad.
问什么不问呢？
Ask me. Why don't you?
你为什么不问？
Why don't you ask?
问我为什么德瓦和我来这里
Ask me why Deva and I came here.
问我为什么他要离婚
Ask me why he wants to get divorced.
来吧！但是你不会问，对吗？
Come on! But you won't, will you?
你知道为什么你不会问吗？
You know why you won't?
因为你讨厌听别人的问题
Because you hate listening to other people's problems.
这是你最讨厌的事情
It's the thing you hate the most.
别人告诉你他们的麻烦事
Someone telling you of their troubles.
爸
Dad...
你甚至不能忍受周围的人生病
You can't even bear it when people are sick around you.
还记得我小时候发烧吗？
Remember the times I had fevers as a kid?
记得你做了什么吗？
Remember what you did? Do you remember?
我来提醒你！你离开了！
I'll remind you. You left.
你离开了家
You left the house.
我曾经尽力祈祷不生病
I used to pray with all my might not to get sick.
不要发烧，这样我的父亲就不会生我的气
Not to get fevers so that my father didn't get mad at me.
你也没照顾妈妈
You didn't look after mom, either.
护士照顾了，我和医生照顾了
The nurses did. I did. father didn't get mad at me.
但是你从来没有
But you never did.
你去医院
You'd come to the hospital.
我会告诉你，“爸爸，妈妈快死了”
I'd tell you, "Dad, mom's dying."
你会说“不”
You'd say "No."
“她很好，妈妈很好”
"She's doing great. Mom's doing great."
因为那是你想听到的
Because that's what you want to hear.
一切都很好没有任何问题
Everything's great. No problems whatsoever.
一切都很完美
Everything's perfect.
如果有用的话，我就说出来 我们没问题，爸爸
I'll say it if it will help. We have no problems, dad.
你是完美的 我是完美的
You're perfect. I'm perfect.
德瓦也是完美的
Deva's perfect.
完美的人生
Life's perfect.
好
Good.
那很好
That's good.
这里是阿加 贝尤鲁
Agah Beyoglu.
-阿加？-努赫特！
- Agah? - Nukhet!
你好吗？
How are you?
我刚刚还在想你
I was just thinking about you.
我搞到了几张票
I was able to find some tickets.
-是吗？-今天晚上你想一起吗？
- Were you now? - It's tonight. Would you like to join me?
当然
Sure.
-什么事？-我们准备好了
- What is it? - We're ready.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
把这些交给他们
Hand these out to the guys.
好了……
Alright...
内芙拉呢？
Where's Nevra?
她从某个地方得到了线报，去了法院进行调查
She got a tip from somewhere. She went to the courthouse to look into it.
你知道穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔吗？
You know Mehmet Yurtgil, the judge?
他因受贿而闻名
He was known for taking bribes.
她在调查被冤枉的嫌疑犯
She's looking into the suspects that were wronged.
她认为有人可能会对他报仇
She thinks someone might've took revenge on him.
好吧，不管怎样
Alright then. Anyway,
我这里有弹道报告，结果是这样：
I have the ballistics report right here. Here's the situation:
用来杀死纳伊姆汉 ·图雷迪的枪
The gun that was used to kill Naimhan Turedi
与用来杀死穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔的那只不匹配
does not match the one used to kill Mehmet Yurtgil.
那枪没有在任何地方注册
That gun wasn't registered anywhere. However...
我们在用来杀死纳伊姆汉 ·图雷迪的枪上有一些线索
We have some leads on the gun that was used to kill Naimhan Turedi.
2001年有人用那把枪开枪并受伤
Someone was shot and wounded with that gun in 2001.
枪应该是被没收了
The gun was seized, and is supposed to be
存放在阿迪坎市警察局的证据储物柜中
in the Ard?chan municipality police department's evidence locker.
但是它消失了，为什么呢？
But it's gone! Why's that?
因为那个证据储物柜已经没有了
Because that evidence locker no longer exists.
你调查的那个混蛋怎么样？
How about... That sleazeball you were looking into?
他跟这些都没有关系
He had nothing to do with it.
好吧……
Alright. Now...
做这些事的人
The individual who did all this shit...
我们暂时叫他图凡
Let's call him Tufan for now.
图凡进入证据储物柜
Tufan gets into the evidence locker.
他盗窃了储物柜，然后
He burglarizes the locker. Then...
他把地方烧了，使它看起来像黑手党做的一样
He burns the place down to make it look like the mafia did it.
所以他对杀人不感兴趣
So he's not interested in killing just anyone.
他不是常规的连环杀手
He's not a regular serial killer.
既然他拥有这么多枪，
Since he's in possession of so many guns,
并假设他不准备卖枪
and assuming he's not interested in selling them,
那么就很明显了
welcome to your own personal hells.
他将要开始屠杀
He's going to commit a massacre.
除非我们先抓到他
Unless we catch him first.
3月18日 周日
MARCH 18 SUNDAY
这是我的简历
Here. Here's my resumé.
谢谢你同意见我 我知道你很忙
Thank you for agreeing to see me. I know you're busy.
很荣幸见到你
It's an honor to meet you.
这没什么意义
This means nothing.
就是这个
This is it.
-您去过哪里？奥地利？-澳大利亚
- Where have you been? Austria? - Australia.
我刚回来
I just got back.
你来的很及时
You're just in time.
我的秘书跟了我20年了，
Melahat, my secretary for 20 years,
上周刚刚退休
was retired just last week.
我猜是巧合吧
Coincidence, I guess.
没有巧合
There are no coincidences.
因为生活本身就是巧合
Because life itself is a coincidence.
一个人连续锁门99天
A man locks the door to his house for 99 days.
在第100天，他忘记锁门
On the 100th day, he forgets to lock the door.
小偷很后悔
The thief repents.
在那99天内，他无视这所房子，
He ignores the house for those 99 days,
但在第100天发现门没锁
but finds the door unlocked on the 100th day.
每天都排着队
The days line up.
你怎么说？
What do you call that?
巧合？
A coincidence?
不是
No.
那是什么？
What is it?
这就是生活
It's life.
你学得很快 祖哈尔
You're a fast learner, Zuhal.
-塞利克 - 贝尤鲁 我姓贝尤鲁
- Celik. - Beyoglu. My surname's Beyoglu.
我要离婚了
I'm getting divorced.
你知道阿加 贝尤鲁吗？他是你的亲戚吗？
Do you know Agah Beyoglu? Is he a relative of yours?
他是我父亲
He's my father.
难以置信
Incredible.
这不是生命这是巧合
Now this, this isn't life. This is coincidence.
他最近好吗？
How is he doing? Well, I hope?
他很好，当然，你怎么认识他？
He's well, of course. How do you know him?
当然是坎布拉 还能是哪里？
From Kambura. Where else?
-检察官？-你知道这件事吗？
- Prosecutor? - Did you know about this?
是杀手还是受害者？
KILLER OR VICTIM?
我知道 那是内芙拉的主意 我告诉她继续做下去
I did. It was Nevra's idea. I told her to go ahead with it.
这是一个愚蠢的冒险
That was a stupid risk to take.
如果图凡被抓了并且一切都暴露了怎么办？
What if Tufan gets caught and everything is revealed?
然后会怎样呢？
What then?
图凡与内芙拉或任何受害者都没有任何关系
Tufan has no connection either to Nevra or to any of the victims.
所以我批准了这篇新闻
That's why I approved the news article.
还有其他人参与
There's someone else involved.
不管是谁在帮图凡
Whoever it is that's helping Tufan
当他意识到我们在追踪他时，他会感到恐慌
will panic when he realizes that we're on his trail.
是你的电话
It's your call.
可是我很不安
But I'm uneasy.
我不确定让内芙拉参与这个案子是否正确
I'm not sure getting Nevra involved in this was the right idea.
您有更好的主意吗？
Do you have any better ideas? No?
那我们继续
Then we proceed.
你有没有告诉菲鲁兹？
Did you tell Firuz?
告诉他了 他在监督内芙拉
I did. He's supervising Nevra.
内芙拉现在在哪里？
Where's Nevra now?
我告诉她如果被发现 她会被踢出警队
I told her she'd be kicked off the force if it was discovered.
她对我撒谎 告诉我她妈妈生病了 去了坎布拉
She's lying to me. Told me her mom was sick. Went to Kambura.
那是她家
That's where she lives.
第二个受害者不就是在那里出生的吗？
Isn't there where the second victim was born?
是的 她可能正在调查
That's right. She could be looking into it.
好 我们有了一些线索
Good. We have some leads, then.
但我不忍心用我的人当诱饵
We do but I can't bear the thought of using one of my people as bait.
你不是有人在跟着她吗？有什么不放心的？
Are you having her followed? You are. So what's the problem?
注意 托尔加
Look here, Tolga.
他近期不会停止杀人
He's not going to stop killing people anytime soon.
谁应该抓住他？是你
Who's supposed to catch him? You are.
唯一的线索是什么？内芙拉
What's the only lead we have? Nevra.
如果你将内芙拉拒之门外，
If you take Nevra off the case,
不管是图凡还是其他人
it won't matter whether it was Tufan or someone else.
你永远都不会抓住凶手
You'll never catch the murderer.
有人犯下这些谋杀罪只是为了让内夫拉设法解决他们
Someone's committing these murders just to get Nevra to try to solve them.
玛雅的装扮世界
MAYA'S COSTUME WORLD
烟会杀死你的，你知道吧
Those things will kill you, you know.
别扔，给我来一支
You don't have to throw it out. Give me one.
-法院有线索了吗？-没有
- Any leads from the courthouse? - No.
我有火
I have a light.
我父亲的打火机
My father's lighter.
他戒烟的那一天把它传给了我
He passed it down to me the day he stopped smoking.
我问他我该怎么办，我那时还没开始抽烟
I asked him what I was supposed to do with it. I didn't even smoke.
我在那天开始抽烟
I picked it up that day.
我父亲戒烟那一天我开始抽烟
I picked up smoking the day my father quit. Ridiculous.
实际上是我妈妈鼓励我抽烟
It was my mom that encouraged me to smoke, actually.
她告诉我如果我抽烟是可以的，但是不应该偷偷摸摸
She told me it was alright if I smoked, but that I shouldn't be sneaky about it.
我不会抽烟，但是我不能告诉她
I didn't smoke, but I couldn't tell her.
我坐在她的对面，点燃了一根烟，与她共度时光
I sat across from her and lit one up just to get to spend some time with her.
我就是这样开始吸烟的
That's how I started smoking.
只是为了和她在一起做点什么事
Just to do the same thing as her at the same time as she did.
她好吗？
How is she? Better?
好多了
Better. She's better.
应该很难吧，彼此相距太远
It must be hard, living so far away from each other.
-我时不时能见到她 -好 不要不见她
- I see her from time to time. - Good. Don't stop seeing her.
我父亲已经死了
My father's dead now.
这就是他剩下的一切
This is all that's left of him.
尼穆尔 -我可爱的猫
MUNIR - MY LOVELY CAT
我好怕死，穆尼尔
I'm so scared of death, Munir.
其实我会告诉你一个秘密
In fact, I'll tell you a secret.
即使地球上的每个人都死了，我也没关系
I'd be OK with it even if everyone on earth died
我是唯一剩下的一个
and I were the only one left.
我的意思是
I mean...
我甚至愿意面对这样的寂寞
I'm even willing to face such loneliness.
如果我来世还记得我所做的一切怎么办？
What if I still remember all I've done in the afterlife?
我不能忍受
I couldn't bear that.
我不能
I couldn't.
爷爷！
Grandpa!
你在做什么？关上门！
What are you doing? Shut the door!
什么
What...
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
关上门！
Shut the door!
来得真不是时候
Such bad timing.
告诉你妈妈 我今晚有事要出门
Tell your mom I have some errands to run tonight.
求你买个电话吧
Get yourself a cell phone, please.
我有电话
I have a phone.
顺便给您介绍一下，这是苏薇达
By the way, let me introduce you guys. Suveyda, my grandfather.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
我希望你做了保护措施
I hope you're using protection.
我无法应付另一个孩子
I can't handle another child.
-我不能停车 -你在做什么？
- I'm not staying. - What are you doing?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我忘了我有事要做
I forgot I had something to do.
我有事 可做我忘了 我不能去了
I have something to do. I'd forgotten. I'm not coming in.
你可以在停车场的另一边掉头
You can make a u-turning side the car park.
你能告诉后面那辆车的车主让我倒车过去吗?
Could you tell the car behind me to let me pass in reverse?
有太多车在等
There are too many cars waiting.
-但我……-请打开你的后备箱
- But I'm... - Open up your boot, please.
但是我很着急 那会浪费很多时间
But I'm in a hurry. That'll be a lot of wasted time.
这是工作程序 规则不是我定的
It's how the procedure works. I don't make the rules.
我向你保证，这辆车不是用天然气发动的
The car doesn't run on natural gas, I assure you.
我相信你，但我还是要看看 请把你的钥匙给我。
I believe you, but I still have to look. Give me your keys, please.
后备箱坏了 打不开
The boot's broken. It doesn't open.
-请把钥匙交给我 -坏了，我告诉你
- Hand me your keys, please. - It's broken, I'm telling you.
好 我等一下
Fine. Give me a minute.
坏了
Broken.
我已经尝试了很多次了，但是打不开
I've tried so many times, but it won't open.
-让我试试，先生 -它不会打开
- Let me try, sir. - It won't open.
-但是，它打不开 -让我试试
- But, it won't open - Let me try.
看！你弄坏了，赔钱吧
Look! You break it, you buy it.
-请原谅哈吉（到麦加朝圣过的伊斯兰教徒） -算了
- Forgive me, Hajji. - It's fine.
-我必须遵守命令 -我明白
- I have to follow the orders. - I understand.
我叔叔也是哈吉 他刚回来
My uncle's a Hajji as well. He just got back.
愿真主保佑他
May Allah bless him.
阿门 阿门
Amen. Amen.
他们说有个杀手在逃 我们有严格的命令
They say there's a killer on the loose. We have strict orders.
我告诉过你很多次了 没有什么可看的
How many times have I told you there was nothing to see?
-请原谅 -很好
- Please forgive me for prying. - It's fine.
人与人之间最基本的信任在哪里
Nobody believes in people anymore.
真是悲哀！
Such a tragedy!
努赫特，原谅我迟到了
Forgive me for being late, Nukhet.
我遇到了些麻烦事
I ran into so many delays.
-别说了 你现在到了 -看起来很棒
- Don't mention it. You're here now. - You look great.
-谢谢你 你也是 -谢谢
- Thank you. So do you. - Thank you.
-我们快进去吧 快开始了 -当然，在您之后
- We should go in, it's about to start. - Of course. After you.
-欢迎 -晚上好
- Welcome. - Good evening.
-谢谢 -您的座位就在那边
- Thank you. - Your seats are right over there.
-谢谢 -谢谢你们
- Thank you. - Thank you, guys.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
你在做什么？你是谁？
What are you doing? Who are you?
回答我！
Answer me!
没有人能夺走生命
No mortal can take this life.
他们不能忍受
They can't bear it.
他们否认一切
They deny everything.
他们说谎
They lie.
他们保持安静
They keep quiet.
或丢弃
Or they throw it all up.
或阴谋
Or they plot.
或逃避
Or they run from it.
或偷窃
Or they steal.
或破产
Or they break.
或生育
Or they give birth.
或窒息
Or they suffocate.
或醉酒
Or they get drunk.
或恋爱
Or they fall in love.
或停止
Or they stop moving,
一点一点地死去
and die little by little.
他们枯萎
They wilt.
他们质疑
They question.
他们生气
They get mad.
他们不满
They get resentful.
他们射精
They ejaculate.
他们抓住
They seize up.
他们相信
They believe.
他们创造
They get created.
他们打架
They fight.
他们受伤
They get wounded.
他们尝试
They try...
他们尝试然后错了
They try, and get it wrong.
他们尝试，
They try,
然后错了
and get it wrong.
尝试弄错
Try and get it wrong.
良心类似于内心
Conscience resembles the gut.
即使您在睡觉时，它也在不停地工作
It keeps working away even while you're asleep.
无论您有多么否认自己的良心，
No matter how much you deny your conscience,
你犯下的可怕的谋杀案
that horrible murder you've committed
会永远成为你被吊住的绳索
always becomes the rope you get hung by.
它缠绕在你的脖子上，
It wraps around your neck,
你受害者手上的油乎乎的绳子
the oily pieces of rope your victim has for hands.
你基本不知道你杀的是什么
You seldom know what it is you've murdered.
但你仍然每天晚上都在梦中吊死自己
But you still keep hanging yourself every night in your dreams.
内心很像良心
The gut resembles the conscience.
如果您要清空其中的内容
If you're looking to empty it of its contents,
你会找到一个地方做
you'll find somewhere to do it.
人
Man...
尝试，并弄错了
Tries, and gets it wrong.
人尝试并弄错了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
人尝试并弄错了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
人尝试并弄错了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
阿加，你还好吗？
Agah, are you alright?
我受不了了
I can't take it anymore.
尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
这是艺术？
This is art?
抱歉
Sorry.
他们称之为艺术？这是什么？
They call it art? What is this?
尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
那是我第一次在结束前离开
That's the first time I've left a play before the curtain.
我认为这很荒谬
I thought it was ridiculous.
幸好离开的早，我要无聊死了
It's good that we left early. I was bored out of my mind.
我一直想告诉你一些事情，但是我一直没找到合适的机会
I've been meaning to tell you something, but I've never found the right time.
当我来医院看望您时，您的女儿祖哈尔似乎遭受了重创
When I came to visit you at the hospital, your daughter Zuhal was devastated.
-她说了些不体面的话 -不，恰恰相反
- Did she say something inconsiderate. - No. Just the opposite.
她说了一些让我感动的事
She said something that moved me.
你告诉她那天晚上你在我家过夜了
You told her that you were staying over at my place that night you had your accident.
你说我是你女朋友
You said I was your girlfriend.
至少那是她的印象
At least that's the impression she'd gotten.
-你说什么？-我说你和我在一起
- What did you say? - I said that you were with me.
我确信你有你的理由
I'm sure you had your reasons.
-我不会揭穿你-你真好
- I wouldn't speak against you. - You're so kind.
谢谢
Thank you.
我独居了很长时间
I've been living on my own for such a long time...
我已经习惯了
I've gotten used to it.
但有时也会变得无聊
But it does get boring from time to time.
有时候我一个人出去玩
I go out on my own sometimes,
但我不想让他们担心我
but I don't want them to worry about me.
请原谅我那样让你为难
Forgive me for putting you on the spot like that.
你知道我内心怎么想吗？
You know what I said to myself?
我希望他真的能来我家
I wish he'd really stayed over.
亲爱的内芙拉 埃尔马斯，祝你生日快乐 阿提斯
DEAR NEVRA ELMAS, WE WISH YOU A HAPPY BIRTHDAY. ARTI BANK.
这蛋糕很好吃 你买的吗？
This cake's delicious. Did you buy it?
是的，塞利姆 吃吧
Yes, Selim. Enjoy.
你生日那天我给你买一个
I'll get you one on your birthday.
-什么时候？-别操心了
- When's that, by the way? - Don't worry about it.
-我们讨论过的…… -什么？
- About what we talked about... - What was that?
那座山上的房子？
That house on the hill?
内斯林讨厌说起它，这就是为什么我什么也不能说的原因
Nesrin hates talking about it, that's why I couldn't say anything.
但是那里曾发生过一起惨案
But there was a tragedy there.
十年前
It was ten years ago.
你去上大学了
You were away at college.
一家人搬到山上的那所房子里
A family came and moved in to that house on the hill.
此后不久，发生了几起盗窃案
Shortly thereafter, there were a few burglaries.
每个人都怪罪新搬来的那家人
Everybody blamed the new family.
一天晚上，人们变得疯狂起来
One night, the people worked themselves into a frenzy.
年轻人，老人，所有人……
Young, old, everyone...
他们决定驱逐这家人
They decided to drive the family away.
他们包围了房子
They surrounded the house.
大喊 并且扔石头
Shouting, throwing rocks...
那家人太害怕了不敢出门
The family was too scared to come out of the house.
然后，我不知道是谁，但是有人把火把扔到了屋子里
And then, I don't know who, but someone threw a torch at the house.
点着了
It flared up...
把房子烧了
and burned the house down.
里面有五个孩子
Five children inside.
还有爸爸妈妈
And the mom and dad.
他们都被烧死了
They all burned up.
谁扔的火把？
Who threw the torch?
没有人会说
No one would talk.
警察审问了他们所有人，但是没人愿意说
The police interrogated all of them, but no one would say anything.
过了没多久，就被完全遗忘了
It was completely forgotten after a while.
每个人都不再谈论
Everyone had stopped talking about it.
房子还在那儿，烧焦了
The house is still up there, burned to a crisp.
甚至没有人愿意拆掉它
No one even bothered to tear it down.
没有人为此烦恼 他们只是路过
No one is bothered by it. They might walk by it,
但他们不去想它，所以他们甚至都没有注意到
but they don't want to think about it, so they don't even notice it.
那天晚上，纳伊姆汉 ·图雷迪在那里吗？
Was Naimhan Turedi there on that night?
当然
Of course.
他所有的朋友，他的亲戚，他认识的每个人都在那里
All his friends, his relatives, everyone he knew was there.
塞费尔也在那 亚库普和他的叔叔都在
Sefer was there. Yakup and his uncle, as well.
他们喝醉了
They were drunk.
他们在雷扎的家喝醉了
They'd gotten smashed at R?za's place.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know about it?
我经常梦到
It haunts my dreams.
以前不这样的
It didn't use to,
但是随着年龄的增长人们会改变
but people change as they get older.
说起来容易
Easy to say...
七人被杀
Seven people were killed.
孩子都还很小
The children were so small.
谁仍的火把，塞利姆？
Who threw the torch, Selim?
我没看到！
I didn't see him!
我……
I...
我只扔了一块石头
I only threw a single stone.
现在过去好吗？
Is this a bad time?
今天是内芙拉的生日 我有一件礼物送给她
TODAY IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY I GOT HER A BIRTHDAY PRESENT